[
  {
    "id": "01",
    "question": "Which of the following best suits to Java ?",
    "options": [
      "A procedural programming language",
      "An Object - oriented programming language",
      "A Query language",
      "All of these"
    ],
    "answer": "An Object - oriented programming language"
  },
  {
    "id": "02",
    "question": "An aggregation model refers to which of the following relationships?",
    "options": [
      "'is - a' relationship",
      "'has - a' relationship",
      "'a - part - of' relationship",
      "All of these"
    ],
    "answer": "'has - a' relationship"
  },
  {
    "id": "03",
    "question": "Which of the following is not a visibility symbol?",
    "options": ["-", "*", "#", "-"],
    "answer": "*"
  },
  {
    "id": "04",
    "question": "In which year the object - oriented programming concepts started?",
    "options": ["1990s", "1980s", "1970s", "1960s"],
    "answer": "1960s"
  },
  {
    "id": "05",
    "question": "Which of the following is the popular programming language which support object - oriented ?",
    "options": ["Java", "C++", "VB.net", "All of these"],
    "answer": "All of these"
  },
  {
    "id": "06",
    "question": "In which of the following categories the way of programming can be divided?",
    "options": [
      "Procedural",
      "Object - oriented",
      "Both A & B",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "Both A & B"
  },
  {
    "id": "07",
    "question": "In which paradigm , the focus is on objects ?",
    "options": ["Structural", "Sequential", "Procedural", "Object - oriented"],
    "answer": "Object - oriented"
  },
  {
    "id": "08",
    "question": "Objects are classified using a concept of .....",
    "options": ["Person", "class", "Book", "map"],
    "answer": "class"
  },
  {
    "id": "09",
    "question": "In Object - oriented terminology , characteristics are known as ...",
    "options": ["class", "Objects", "Properties", "None of the above."],
    "answer": "Properties"
  },
  {
    "id": "10",
    "question": "Which of the following describes the object?",
    "options": ["Members", "Attributes", "Methods", "Features"],
    "answer": "Attributes"
  },
  {
    "id": "11",
    "question": "Which of the following is a general concept used to embody all the common features of a particular set of objects?",
    "options": ["class", "state", "Behaviour", "Attributes"],
    "answer": "class"
  },
  {
    "id": "12",
    "question": "What is not protected from modification in procedural programming?",
    "options": ["Function", "data", "Methods", "Behaviour"],
    "answer": "data"
  },
  {
    "id": "13",
    "question": "Which kind of members of the class are not available directly to outside world?",
    "options": ["Private", "Protected", "Public", "Default"],
    "answer": "Private"
  },
  {
    "id": "14",
    "question": "Which concept hides the complexity ?",
    "options": ["UML diagrams", "Class diagrams", "Abstraction", "Features"],
    "answer": "Abstraction"
  },
  {
    "id": "15",
    "question": "'Polymorphism' means ....",
    "options": [
      "Many forms",
      "Data hiding",
      "A call to a method",
      "Encapsulation"
    ],
    "answer": "Many forms"
  },
  {
    "id": "16",
    "question": "Which of the following may have same methods with same name",
    "options": ["Data", "Function", "Objects", "classes"],
    "answer": "classes"
  },
  {
    "id": "17",
    "question": "With which symbol , basic aggregation is represented ?",
    "options": [
      "Filled diamond",
      "Filled rectangle",
      "Empty diamond",
      "Empty rectangle"
    ],
    "answer": "Empty diamond"
  },
  {
    "id": "18",
    "question": "Between classes , which kind of relationship is represented by aggregation?",
    "options": ["has - a", "a - part - of", "Both A & B", "is - a"],
    "answer": "Both A & B"
  },
  {
    "id": "19",
    "question": "In class diagram, which symbol is used to represent inheritance ?",
    "options": [
      "An arrow pointing to subclass",
      "Two sided arrow which connect subclass and superclass",
      "An arrow pointing to superclass",
      "A single line connecting sub and superclass"
    ],
    "answer": "An arrow pointing to superclass"
  },
  {
    "id": "20",
    "question": "Class diagram Which symbol is used to represent class in class diagram?",
    "options": ["Circle", "Oval", "Rectangle", "None of the above"],
    "answer": "Rectangle"
  }
]
